A completely transparent audit chain on chain,
完全透明的链上审计，
like an audit trail on chain.
就像链上的审计追踪一样。
If your code is not open source, it
如果您的代码不是开源的，那么
is automatically introducing certain backdoors.
会自动引入某些后门。
Codes which cannot be forked and run independently
无法fork并独立运行的代码
causes a situation where users cannot really and truly exit
造成用户无法真正退出的情况
the system.
系统。
And if they can't exist the system,
如果他们不能存在这个系统
like this itself creates a backdoor.
这样本身就创建了一个后门。
So my message here is that it's very important
所以我想传达的信息是，这非常重要
to look at the different licenses,
查看不同的许可证，
look at the different options available.
查看可用的不同选项。
And if you don't choose open source in the right
而如果你不选择开源就对了
and responsible way, that's already
和负责任的方式，这已经
introducing a lot of intermediaries
引入很多中介
that you cannot easily get over.
你无法轻易克服。
And finally, I would like to end off
最后，我想结束
by talking a little bit about what
谈论一下什么
we do at the Secretariat and also giving a short invitation
我们在秘书处这样做，并发出简短的邀请
for all of you to be involved in some capacity.
让你们所有人都以某种身份参与其中。
So just to very briefly introduce the Ethereum
所以只是非常简单地介绍一下以太坊
Foundation's academic secretariat,
基金会学术秘书处，
we want to try and create the conditions under which
我们想尝试创造条件
rigorous academic work and Ethereum's development
严谨的学术工作和以太坊的发展
can go hand in hand and can actually
可以齐头并进并且实际上可以
go and inform each other.
去互相通报一下。
Our long-term vision is to see Ethereum integrated
我们的长期愿景是看到以太坊整合
as a serious research object, one that
作为一个严肃的研究对象
sustains over the longest time horizons,
持续最长的时间范围，
probably outlives a lot of the organizations,
可能比很多组织更长寿，
probably outlives all of us.
可能比我们所有人都长寿。
And this is a very ambitious mission.
这是一个非常雄心勃勃的使命。
And it actually requires people who can very honestly engage
它实际上需要能够非常诚实地参与的人
with these problems.
与这些问题。
So if you're a researcher and you're
所以如果你是一名研究人员并且你
looking to get more involved in Ethereum,
希望更多地参与以太坊，
please feel free to reach out.
请随时与我们联系。
If you're someone from the application groups
如果您是应用程序组的成员
or like the industry who's looking
或者喜欢正在寻找的行业
to get their problems in front of the right academics
将他们的问题摆在合适的学者面前
or who's looking to seriously test and rigorously test
或者谁想要认真测试和严格测试
where all their assumptions break down,
他们所有的假设都崩溃了，
please do reach out to us.
请联系我们。
We are always willing to engage with people who can help us
我们总是愿意与能够帮助我们的人交往
in this ambitious mission.
在这个雄心勃勃的使命中。
And yeah, that's my time.
是的，那是我的时间。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
You can reach me at my email, or you can also
您可以通过我的电子邮件联系我，或者您也可以
reach me on Twitter.
在 Twitter 上联系我。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Thank you, Xuan.
谢谢你，轩。
While we get the stage set up of our next session,
当我们为下一次会议搭建舞台时，
a quick note for those who may just join us.
给那些可能刚刚加入我们的人的简短说明。
Today's gathering is hosted by the Ethereum Application
今天的聚会由以太坊应用程序主办
or EAG, a global nonprofit collaborative organization
或 EAG，一个全球非营利合作组织
dedicated to advancing the innovation, adoption,
致力于推进创新、采用、
and real world impact of Ethereum native applications.
以及以太坊本机应用程序对现实世界的影响。
Next up, we are moving to chapter two.
接下来，我们将进入第二章。
What should we build now to shift to real applications?
我们现在应该构建什么来转向实际应用程序？
We will discuss what meaningful Ethereum applications look
我们将讨论有意义的以太坊应用程序是什么样的
like today and how to distinguish real signals
就像今天一样以及如何区分真实信号
from noise.
来自噪音。
A panel on From Data to Deployment
关于从数据到部署的小组讨论
in Serum in Real-World Systems, moderated
真实世界系统中的血清，主持
by Du Yu, General Manager of Wan Xiang Blockchain Labs.
作者：杜宇，万向区块链实验室总经理。
The panelists are Rachel Li, Director of Blockchain
小组成员为区块链总监 Rachel Li
and Digital Assets of Cyberport, Colin Cao, CEO of JetBay,
和数码港数字资产，JetBay 首席执行官 Colin Cao，
and Kevin Wong, co-founder of Codata.
和 Codata 联合创始人 Kevin Wong。
Please welcome them all.
请大家欢迎他们。
Good afternoon, everyone.
大家下午好。
It's already past lunchtime.
已经过了午饭时间了。
Today, we have invited a few experts
今天，我们邀请了几位专家
from the industrial industry to join us at the Ethereum Application Alliance.
来自工业界的人士加入我们的以太坊应用联盟。
The main purpose of this panel is to discuss
该小组的主要目的是讨论
how to better support Ethereum in real-world applications,
如何在现实应用中更好地支持以太坊，
non-financial applications, and how to make Ethereum
非金融应用程序，以及如何制作以太坊
a better financial infrastructure for AI development and data development.
为人工智能开发和数据开发提供更好的金融基础设施。
This panel will be related to data.
该面板将与数据相关。
AI is very popular recently, but the core of AI is data.
人工智能最近很流行，但人工智能的核心是数据。
Whether you use AI or train,
无论你使用AI还是训练，
the most important step is to build a database of data.
最重要的一步是建立数据数据库。
That's why we have this session today.
这就是我们今天召开这次会议的原因。
First of all, I would like to ask the guests to introduce themselves.
首先请嘉宾做一下自我介绍。
Let's start with Rachel.
让我们从雷切尔开始吧。
Thank you very much, Mr. Du and everyone.
非常感谢杜先生和大家。
I am Rachel from Shumangang, Hong Kong.
我是来自香港舒曼岗的Rachel。
I used to work in finance.
我以前从事金融工作。
In the past three years, I have witnessed the whole of Hong Kong's WES3.
这三年来，我见证了整个香港的WES3。
Since then, more and more companies have joined us.
从那时起，越来越多的公司加入了我们。
Three years ago, we established WES3 Hub in Shumangang.
三年前，我们在舒曼岗建立了WES3 Hub。
At that time, there were seven or eight WES3 companies.
当时WES3公司有七八家。
Now, there are more than 310 companies.
目前，已有企业310多家。
We can see the real development of Hong Kong.
我们可以看到香港真实的发展。
Now, there are many more native companies,
现在本土企业越来越多，
such as DeFi and other cross-chain protocols.
比如 DeFi 等跨链协议。
There are also many traditional industries,
还有很多传统产业，
including RWA and payment.
包括 RWA 和付款。
Payment and AI are more common.
支付和人工智能更加普遍。
These are some of the development directions we have seen recently.
这些是我们最近看到的一些发展方向。
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家。
Next guest.
下一位客人。
Hello, everyone.
大家好。
My name is Chaoyuan.
我叫朝元。
I am an airline entrepreneur.
我是一名航空公司企业家。
You may find it strange.
你可能会觉得很奇怪。
The combination of airline industry and WES3.0 is like this.
航空业与WES3.0的结合就是这样。
In fact, we are a data service provider in the field of airline industry.
事实上，我们是航空业领域的数据服务提供商。
In the past seven years,
在过去的七年里，
we have been digging deep into airline industry data.
我们一直在深入挖掘航空业数据。
In the past, there were relatively few applications of airline industry data.
过去，航空行业数据的应用相对较少。
Now, we can combine airline industry data
现在，我们可以结合航空业数据
with WES3.0's basic facilities
具备WES3.0的基础设施
to make it more profitable and become a real living asset.
使其更有利可图并成为真正的活资产。
Then, we can provide new value in our industry.
然后，我们可以为我们的行业提供新的价值。
Okay, next guest.
好的，下一位客人。
Kevin.
凯文.
Thank you for inviting me.
谢谢你邀请我。
Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Kevin, I am the founder of CoreData.
凯文，我是 CoreData 的创始人。
We did CoreData quite early.
我们很早就做了 CoreData。
Now, everyone knows about AI.
现在，每个人都知道人工智能。
In fact, everyone is familiar with the industry and the company's business model.
事实上，每个人都熟悉这个行业和公司的商业模式。
We were the first to provide AI training data to large model companies.
我们是第一个向大型模型公司提供AI训练数据的公司。
Now, we focus on data collection and marking for medical companies
现在，我们专注于医疗公司的数据收集和标记
and machine companies in China and the United States.
以及中国和美国的机械公司。
At that time, CoreData was also a data service provider
当时CoreData也是一家数据服务商
in the early days of Shumagang.
在蜀马岗初期。
It was also a data service provider in the early days of Wanxiang.
万向早期也是一家数据服务商。
This year, Ethereum issued an agreement of 804 and 402.
今年，以太坊发布了804和402协议。
It provided us with more payment between agents
它为我们提供了更多的代理商之间的付款方式
and provided us with more possibilities
并为我们提供了更多的可能性
to expand later.
以后再扩展。
Okay, thank you for your introduction.
好的，谢谢你的介绍。
My first question is for Kevin.
我的第一个问题是问凯文的。
In my opinion, CoreData solves the issue of data security and back-to-back distribution.
在我看来，CoreData解决了数据安全和背靠背分发的问题。
Because when you do a lot of model training,
因为当你进行大量模型训练时，
you need data from many different sources.
您需要来自许多不同来源的数据。
So, what kind of benefits do you think blockchain can bring you in this field?
那么，您认为区块链能够在这个领域给您带来哪些好处呢？
How did you come up with the idea of combining Web3 and data in this industry?
您是如何想到将 Web3 与这个行业的数据相结合的想法的？
That's a good question.
这是个好问题。
In fact, a lot of people asked this question in the beginning of last year.
其实去年年初就有很多人问过这个问题。
They discussed the combination of AI and crypto.
他们讨论了人工智能和加密货币的结合。
They tried various things.
他们尝试了各种各样的事情。
What we saw was an intersection between AI data and crypto.
我们看到的是人工智能数据和加密货币之间的交叉点。
At that time, we were just getting started.
那时，我们才刚刚开始。
In fact, in the traditional market,
事实上，在传统市场上，
there is also a way to provide the United States with skill AI and color AI.
还有一个办法就是给美国提供技能AI和色彩AI。
Of course, it's a storyline.
当然，这是一个故事情节。
We can use crypto to do this better.
我们可以使用加密技术来更好地做到这一点。
We are also thinking about how to do it better.
我们也在思考如何做得更好。
In the first step, we didn't use the source and trace.
在第一步中，我们没有使用源和跟踪。
There are actually two points.
其实有两点。
First, we want to use the incentive mechanism of crypto tokenization
首先，我们要利用加密代币化的激励机制
to make my global annotator better to make more marks for our real business.
让我的全局注释器变得更好，为我们的实际业务做出更多标记。
When our business is more stable,
当我们的业务更加稳定的时候，
our real customers are more concerned about
我们真正的客户更关心
whether they can get skill AI to the level of data.
他们能否将技能人工智能提升到数据水平。
What are the advantages of CoreData?
CoreData有什么优势？
First, we can track who is contributing how much to each level.
首先，我们可以跟踪谁为每个级别贡献了多少。
And I don't sell data to you all at once.
而且我不会一次性把数据卖给你们。
If I sell it to Meta today,
如果我今天把它卖给 Meta，
I may sell it to OpenAI.
我可能会把它卖给 OpenAI。
But I know that the contributor's data has been reselled.
但我知道贡献者的数据已被转售。
I can track it through this blockchain.
我可以通过这个区块链追踪它。
It continues to make contributions.
并持续做出贡献。
It will continue to get its profits in the process of reselling.
它将在转售过程中不断获得利润。
This is actually more down to earth.
这其实更接地气。
Blockchain is really helping us to solve
区块链确实在帮助我们解决
the whole lineage of data sources,
数据源的整个谱系，
including the whole contribution calculation.
包括整个贡献的计算。
What you just said is more about
你刚才说的更多的是
how we can collect more multi-dimensional data
我们如何收集更多多维数据
to train AI more
进一步训练AI
and monetize these data.
并将这些数据货币化。
When I was communicating with Mr. Cao,
当我和曹老师交流的时候，
Mr. Cao just said that he is an aerospace engineer.
曹先生刚才说他是一名航天工程师。
I was wondering how to combine this with YF3.
我想知道如何将它与 YF3 结合起来。
In fact, when I was communicating with Mr. Cao,
其实我和曹老师交流的时候，
I suddenly found that in our imagination,
我突然发现，在我们的想象中，
aerospace is also a very high-tech field.
航空航天也是一个非常高科技的领域。
If you go on a business trip or take a plane every day,
如果你每天出差或者坐飞机，
it's the most advanced technology.
这是最先进的技术。
Everything you see is very advanced.
你所看到的一切都是非常先进的。
But when I was communicating with Mr. Cao,
但当我和曹老师交流的时候，
I found that in operation,
我发现在操作中，
there are a lot of traditional ways
有很多传统的方法
to operate in the aviation industry
从事航空业
or in the entire civil aviation system.
或在整个民航系统中。
There are a lot of data isolation.
有很多数据隔离。
So I think YF3 can play a big role in this industry.
所以我认为YF3可以在这个行业发挥很大的作用。
First, how to solve the problem of data isolation.
首先，如何解决数据隔离问题。
Second, everyone has a lot of broken data.
其次，每个人都有很多破损的数据。
How to connect these data
如何连接这些数据
to make the aviation industry better digitized and intelligent.
让航空业更好地数字化、智能化。
And furthermore,
而且，此外，
after having the data,
得到数据后，
a lot of venues have been talking about
很多场馆都在谈论
tokenization and RWA.
代币化和 RWA。
Mr. Cao, what kind of opportunity do you see in this?
曹先生，您认为这其中有什么样的机会？
Mr. Du, we have discussed this before.
杜先生，这个问题我们之前讨论过。
The aviation industry is an industry
航空业是一个产业
that relies on data to drive.
依靠数据来驱动。
In fact, because of data,
事实上，因为数据，
we say data isolation.
我们说数据隔离。
In the aviation industry,
在航空业中，
it is not only a problem of data isolation,
这不仅仅是数据隔离的问题，
but also a problem of data quality.
但同时也是数据质量的问题。
Because sometimes we find that
因为有时我们会发现
the quality of these data from a data source
来自数据源的这些数据的质量
is incomparable.
是无与伦比的。
In fact, it will bring a lot of misunderstandings
其实会带来很多误会
to the end users of these data.
这些数据的最终用户。
So when we do the AVGO project,
所以当我们做AVGO项目的时候，
the first problem we have to solve is
我们要解决的第一个问题是
how to form a high-quality data
如何形成高质量的数据
for the entire aviation industry.
对于整个航空业。
This data comes from,
该数据来自，
we say, a plane being produced
我们说，正在生产一架飞机
and put into operation by this plane.
并由这架飞机投入运行。
All kinds of data from the airport
机场各类数据
and maintenance.
和维护。
So these data,
那么这些数据，
I often say that the aviation industry
我经常说航空业
is more like a insurance industry.
更像是一个保险行业。
It especially needs to calculate.
尤其需要计算。
For example,
例如，
we say that some airlines
我们说有些航空公司
have very high operating efficiency
具有非常高的运行效率
and very good profits.
以及非常好的利润。
How does the profit come?
利润是怎么来的？
How to drive it through data?
如何通过数据来驱动它？
Do you know that
你知道吗
some airlines will even
有些航空公司甚至会
ask our pilots
询问我们的飞行员
how many minutes
多少分钟
they will take
他们会采取
to get on the plane
上飞机
and what kind of
以及什么样的
power they will use
他们将使用的权力
to step on the throttle.
踩油门。
This data can bring
这个数据可以带来
for example, spring and autumn.
例如，春季和秋季。
In the spring and autumn,
在春天和秋天，
through the specific movement
通过具体的动作
of these pilots,
这些飞行员​​中，
the blue oil will bring
蓝色的油会带来
the oil consumption to 1.3 billion.
石油消耗达到13亿。
So the aviation industry is very dependent
所以航空业非常依赖
on this high-quality data
在这个高质量的数据上
to drive it.
来驱动它。
This is my first impression.
这是我的第一印象。
The second one is about the RWA.
第二个是关于 RWA 的。
Sometimes we say that
有时我们会这么说
aviation industry is a heavy asset industry.
航空业是重资产行业。
A plane costs a few hundred million.
一架飞机要几亿。
It's easy for us to say that
我们很容易说
what about assets?
资产呢？
In aviation industry,
在航空业中，
we think that there is a very big chance.
我们认为机会很大。
But the key is
但关键是
the value of assets
资产价值
and the operating value
和营业价值
of assets.
资产。
In fact, there are two parts.
事实上，有两个部分。
The value of assets
资产价值
and the added value
和附加值
of its operation.
其运作。
Combining them together
将它们组合在一起
is the biggest scale
是最大的规模
to play the value of assets.
发挥资产价值。
I think in the WIP-3 era,
我认为在WIP-3时代，
aviation industry should have
航空业应该有
a lot of opportunities
很多机会
to improve efficiency.
以提高效率。
Because we are facing
因为我们面临
the entire user scale of AVGO.
AVGO的整个用户规模。
Maybe we can reach
也许我们可以到达
more than a million individual users
超过百万个人用户
and 50,000 corporate users this year.
今年还有 50,000 家企业用户。
Those corporate users
那些企业用户
who use these data on the AVGO platform
谁在 AVGO 平台上使用这些数据
will find that the enterprise
就会发现企业
is not so blind anymore.
不再那么盲目了。
When everyone is doing this,
当大家都这样做的时候，
I think the efficiency is higher.
我觉得效率比较高。
So now, from 2024,
所以现在，从 2024 年开始，
aviation industry found
航空业发现
the destruction of
的破坏
large-scale aviation industry.
航空工业规模宏大。
We don't need the traditional way
我们不需要传统的方式
to sell and promote anymore.
不再销售和促销。
Instead, we use the data platform
相反，我们使用数据平台
to improve our efficiency.
来提高我们的效率。
In fact,
实际上，
whether it is data-driven
是否是数据驱动的
or AI-driven,
或人工智能驱动，
it brings a lot of opportunities
它带来了很多机会
to improve efficiency
提高效率
and new business model
和新的商业模式
in many mainstream or traditional industries.
在许多主流或传统行业。
In the past two years,
在过去的两年里，
we have made a lot of
我们做了很多
investments in AI in Hong Kong.
香港人工智能投资。
In addition to the fact that
除此之外，
there are hundreds of companies
有数百家公司
in the world,
在世界上，
we have also built a large AI data center.
我们还建设了大型人工智能数据中心。
Recently,
最近，
we have been discussing
我们一直在讨论
a lot of financial applications.
很多金融应用。
A few days ago,
日前，
many officials in Hong Kong
香港多位官员
were talking about financial supervision.
谈到金融监管。
Have you seen any interesting
有没有看到什么有趣的
applications
应用
that combine with AI
与AI结合
and data?
和数据？
Or do you think there will be
或者你认为会有
interesting applications in the future
未来有趣的应用
in the field of Web3, AI, and data-driven?
在Web3、人工智能和数据驱动领域？
OK, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
In fact, there must be a lot in this area.
事实上，这方面一定有很多。
Some are still in the early stages.
有些仍处于早期阶段。
But in fact,
但事实上，
there is a lot of potential in the future.
未来有很大的潜力。
In fact,
实际上，
in terms of DID,
就DID而言，
it will be a very important bridge.
这将是一座非常重要的桥梁。
In terms of AI agents,
在AI代理方面，
how do you give them
你如何给他们
an identity?
一个身份？
In terms of data
从数据来看
or in terms of
或就
payment,
支付，
we have seen
我们已经看到了
a relatively important part.
比较重要的一个部分。
Recently,
最近，
in terms of
按照
stable currency,
稳定币，
it is closely related to DID.
与DID密切相关。
If you hope that
如果你希望这样
the adoption
收养
will be higher,
会更高，
and
和
in terms of
按照
different aspects,
不同的方面，
we have seen
我们已经看到了
some traditional custodian companies
一些传统托管公司
or traditional
或传统的
payment companies.
支付公司。
Many of them
他们中的许多人
are already doing it.
已经在这样做了。
Some have already launched
有的已经上线了
some wallets for agents.
一些给代理商的钱包。
In this aspect,
在这方面，
we see
我们看到
that they have a lot of assets.
他们拥有大量资产。
After all, they are native
毕竟他们都是本土人
and use encrypted currency
并使用加密货币
to pay.
支付。
This should have a big impact
这应该有很大的影响
on any industry.
在任何行业。
We also see
我们还看到
some AI companies.
一些人工智能公司。
AI itself is a productivity.
AI本身就是一种生产力。
It generates a lot of content.
它产生了大量的内容。
Some companies
部分企业
use this
用这个
to make a lot of movies
拍很多电影
or
或者
animations.
动画。
They are also
他们也是
looking at how to use
看看如何使用
to combine
结合
RWA
随机加权平均法
and other ways
和其他方式
to
到
pay
支付
for their own rights and benefits
为了自己的权利和利益
or IP.
或IP。
This is a new
这是一个新的
way of playing.
演奏方式。
So,
所以，
in these different areas,
在这些不同的领域，
we see that
我们看到
some companies are already doing it.
一些公司已经在这样做了。
But I think
但我认为
if we really want to use
如果我们真的想使用
large-scale applications,
大规模应用，
it will take some time.
这需要一些时间。
When Richard was introducing,
当理查德介绍时，
you may find that
你可能会发现
the entire digital economy
整个数字经济
of WIFE 3
妻子 3
is still in a state
仍处于状态
where a lot of infrastructure is being supplemented.
许多基础设施正在得到补充。
For example, DID.
例如，DID。
DID has been talked about for many years.
DID 已经被谈论很多年了。
I think it's a good time for
我认为这是一个好时机
people to use it.
人们使用它。
For example, Mr. Cao,
比如曹先生，
they need a lot of resources.
他们需要大量资源。
But the solution
但解决办法
is not that mature.
还没有那么成熟。
If you have,
如果你有，
please let us know.
请告诉我们。
We hope to have more projects like this.
我们希望有更多这样的项目。
In fact, I think
其实我觉得
WIFE 3 is in a good position.
WIFE 3处于有利位置。
It can see
它可以看到
the different areas of the industry
行业的不同领域
from the infrastructure,
从基础设施来看，
and it will know that
它会知道
when the entire industry is developing,
当整个行业都在发展的时候，
we still lack something
我们还缺少一些东西
in terms of technology and service.
在技​​术和服务方面。
In fact, many people
事实上，很多人
sometimes do some so-called
有时会做一些所谓的
follow-up or set up questions.
跟进或设置问题。
I think WIFE 3
我觉得老婆3
can give us a lot of
可以给我们很多
WIFE 3 entrepreneurs
妻子3位企业家
some guidance to say
一些指导说
which companies have what needs.
哪些企业有哪些需求。
You have a lot of connection with many big companies.
您与许多大公司有很多联系。
Thank you, Mr. Du.
谢谢杜先生。
I think there are some
我认为有一些
traditional companies.
传统企业。
If they need some
如果他们需要一些
technology solutions,
技术解决方案，
including those related to WIFE 3,
包括与WIFE 3有关的，
they will come to us
他们会来找我们
to see if there are any suitable companies.
看看有没有合适的公司。
Then we can make a bridge
然后我们可以做一座桥
to connect both sides.
连接双方。
So I'll go back to Codata.
那么我将回到Codata。
You can tell us
你可以告诉我们
what kind of
什么样的
image your customers have.
您的客户的形象。
Rachel can introduce
雷切尔可以介绍一下
what kind of customers
什么样的客户
have similar needs.
有类似的需求。
What kind of services
什么样的服务
will you provide to customers
你会提供给客户吗
and solve their problems?
并解决他们的问题？
For example, we can take Mr. Cao's
例如，我们可以拿曹先生的
data from the aviation industry.
来自航空业的数据。
For example, you can give them
例如，您可以给他们
the data of the industry,
行业数据，
whether they are
他们是否是
players, providers,
玩家、提供商、
or service providers.
或服务提供商。
What kind of services
什么样的服务
can you provide?
你能提供吗？
Thank you, Mr. Du.
谢谢杜先生。
This is a very good question.
这是一个很好的问题。
Please help me introduce the customers.
请帮我介绍一下客户。
When Codata first started,
当 Codata 刚开始时，
it was very crypto-native.
它是非常加密原生的。
So in the beginning,
所以一开始，
we targeted the transaction
我们瞄准了交易
of the address on the chain
链上地址
and the authenticity
和真实性
of the address.
地址的。
Then we provided some rules
然后我们提供了一些规则
for North America.
对于北美。
Of course, AI is popular these two years,
当然这两年AI很流行，
so we have more clients
所以我们有更多的客户
in the past year.
在过去的一年里。
One of them is a hot robot,
其中之一是炙手可热的机器人，
and the other one is medical.
另一种是医疗方面的。
Medical is a bit simpler.
医疗就简单一些。
In the medical field,
在医疗领域，
people want to try
人们想尝试
medical model.
医疗模型。
But there are many details,
但还有很多细节，
such as the breast or
例如乳房或
a rare disease.
一种罕见的疾病。
Usually, a picture
通常，一张图片
needs a lot of doctors to mark it.
需要很多医生来标记。
In one hour,
一小时内，
the value is about
该值约为
1 to 200 US dollars.
1至200美元。
In this direction,
朝这个方向，
some clients will give it to us,
有些客户会把它给我们，
including domestic and overseas
包括国内和海外
companies that need to be listed.
需要上市的公司。
For example,
例如，
I have a batch of medical data
我有一批医疗数据
or patient data.
或患者数据。
I need a more professional doctor
我需要更专业的医生
in Europe and America.
在欧洲和美洲。
Codata is still a bridge in the middle.
Codata仍然是中间的一座桥梁。
It's a professional mark.
这是一个专业的标志。
I think the audience here
我想这里的观众
is starting to get familiar with the robot.
开始熟悉机器人。
There is a very popular video
有一个非常受欢迎的视频
in India.
在印度。
All the Indian workers
所有的印度工人
are wearing an iPhone
戴着 iPhone
and collecting data.
并收集数据。
The idea is that
这个想法是
the robot in China
机器人在中国
is a very popular direction.
是一个非常热门的方向。
Some traditional real estate owners
一些传统的房地产业主
are coming in
正在进来
to build a real equipment factory.
打造真正的装备工厂。
They get the data.
他们得到数据。
Of course, the robot is still learning
当然，机器人仍在学习中
in the early stages.
在早期阶段。
The learning of the original data
原始数据的学习
is still very useful.
还是很有用的。
But now everyone has begun
但现在大家都开始了
to evolve to the next step.
才能进化到下一步。
For example,
例如，
your real-time data
您的实时数据
or the data of human hands
或者人手的数据
or the data of remote control,
或远程控制的数据，
where is your starting point?
你的出发点在哪里？
Where is the starting point?
起点在哪里？
If the robot fails after learning,
如果机器人学习后出现故障，
what borders does it have?
它有什么边界？
This requires the real person,
这就需要真实的人，
the human loop, to intervene.
人类循环，进行干预。
At that time, we did a big event
当时我们办了一个大活动
with BN.
与国阵。
We had several million
我们有几百万
effective users around the world.
世界各地的有效用户。
Now we can guarantee that
现在我们可以保证
there are about 70-80,000
大约有70-80,000
active users around the world.
全球活跃用户。
Even in Europe and the US,
即使在欧洲和美国，
there are some high-end users.
还有一些高端用户。
Usually, these materials
通常，这些材料
will give us the data.
会给我们数据。
This is our customer's SOP.
这是我们客户的SOP。
For example, in two to three days,
例如，两三天后，
I need to make a random
我需要随机做一个
request.
要求。
This is our current model.
这是我们当前的模型。
Of course, whether it is
当然，无论是
digital or commercial,
数字或商业，
the future of aerospace data
航空航天数据的未来
is also a new
也是一个新的
blue sea market.
蓝海市场。
If this direction of customers
如果客户这个方向
can introduce it to us,
可以给我们介绍一下，
thank you very much, Colin and Richard.
非常感谢科林和理查德。
Thank you, Mr. Du.
谢谢杜先生。
I think
我认为
especially with Mr. Cao's
尤其是曹先生的
relationship with aerospace,
与航空航天的关系，
at the end of each data,
在每个数据的末尾，
it has a very direct effect.
它有非常直接的影响。
Just like what Mr. Cao said earlier,
正如曹先生刚才所说，
like the Spring and Autumn Airlines,
像春秋航空一样，
through very detailed data training,
通过非常详细的数据训练，
it can save costs very well.
它可以很好地节省成本。
In fact, when I talked to Mr. Cao before,
其实我之前跟曹先生聊的时候，
I was very surprised
我很惊讶
that Mr. Cao's J-Bay
那个曹先生的J-Bay
is actually a packaging business.
实际上是一个包装业务。
Then
然后
you will find that after a packaging,
包装之后你会发现，
especially after international flights,
尤其是乘坐国际航班后，
the bill seems to wait at least half a year
账单好像至少要等半年
for a certain amount of money to come out.
为了拿出一定数量的钱。
For example, from Hong Kong to North America,
例如从香港到北美，
its flight will pass
它的航班将会经过
Hong Kong,
香港，
then the mainland,
然后是大陆，
then to Japan, Korea,
然后去日本、韩国、
Alaska, Canada, the United States,
阿拉斯加、加拿大、美国、
it involves a lot of different countries,
它涉及很多不同的国家，
different areas of control,
不同的控制领域，
and then to the local airport.
然后前往当地机场。
Each of them is a lot of different service providers.
他们每个人都是很多不同的服务提供商。
I don't know how they connect
我不知道他们是如何联系的
but the result is
但结果是
that when you have to pay these flight fees,
当你必须支付这些飞行费时
like the local fuel costs,
比如当地的燃油成本，
the bill will take more than half a year
法案需要半年多的时间
to come back.
回来。
Mr. Cao also told me that
曹先生还告诉我
they received the stable currency
他们收到了稳定币
very early overseas to pay.
国外很早就付款了。
In fact, there is a lot of
事实上，有很多
efficiency in this place.
这个地方的效率。
So, Mr. Cao,
那么，曹先生，
you seem to have provided a lot today
你今天似乎提供了很多
from the data sharing training,
从数据共享培训来看，
or from the financial payment,
或从财务付款中，
including the asset currencyization
包括资产货币化
we just talked about.
我们刚才谈到了。
Do you think
你认为
why hasn't everyone started using it yet?
为什么大家还没有开始使用它？
Or is it because
或者是因为
today's website is not mature enough?
现在的网站还不够成熟吗？
Or is it because they don't know about it?
还是因为他们不知道？
Or is it because of other reasons?
还是因为其他原因？
What do you think are the opportunities
您认为有哪些机会
for everyone in the future?
对于未来的每个人？
OK.
好的。
I think Kevin's sharing is actually quite good.
我觉得Kevin的分享其实还不错。
The aviation industry
航空业
is actually not
实际上不是
the stage
舞台
where they haven't started using these technologies
他们还没有开始使用这些技术
yet.
然而。
How do we do
我们该怎么办
the aviation data
航空数据
ourselves?
我们自己？
When we started doing it
当我们开始做的时候
seven years ago, we found that
七年前，我们发现
the aviation data
航空数据
is almost a very low-quality data vacuum.
几乎是一个质量非常低的数据真空。
So, for example,
所以，举例来说，
if you want to have the data
如果你想获得数据
of tens of thousands of airports
数以万计的机场
in the world,
在世界上，
what should you do?
你应该做什么？
You have to build a data team
你必须建立一个数据团队
to do this kind of thing.
做这种事。
So, we have been using
所以，我们一直在使用
the self-building model for the past few years.
过去几年的自建模式。
But what is
但什么是
the drawback of this self-building data?
这种自建数据的缺点是什么？
It is your efficiency.
这是你的效率。
Of course, now that
当然，现在既然
AI has appeared,
AI出现了，
our efficiency has changed a lot.
我们的效率发生了很大的变化。
In the previous data team,
在之前的数据团队中，
we had almost 80
我们有将近 80 个
colleagues to do the data.
同事做数据。
Now, our staff
现在，我们的工作人员
are slowly doing some optimization.
正在慢慢做一些优化。
The data of the aviation industry
航空业数据
is also slowly changing.
也在慢慢改变。
Of course, these years,
当然，这些年，
we said,
我们说，
the improvement in hardware,
硬件的改进，
manpower, and computing power
人力、计算能力
have brought a lot of
带来了很多
unprecedented changes to the aviation industry.
航空业发生前所未有的变化。
But it may not be that fast.
但可能没那么快。
Kevin just talked about
凯文刚刚谈到
the medical industry.
医疗行业。
Last week,
上星期，
I went to the hospital
我去了医院
to see a patient.
看望病人。
Three doctors
三位医生
saw three different results.
看到了三个不同的结果。
The aviation industry
航空业
is slowly
正在慢慢地
changing.
改变。
We are the company
我们是公司
that does high-quality
做高质量的
data mining
数据挖掘
in the aviation industry.
在航空业。
I would like to talk to Kevin about
我想和凯文谈谈
the aviation industry.
航空业。
The industry has a long history.
该行业有着悠久的历史。
From production to production,
从生产到生产，
to operation,
到操作，
Mr. Du,
杜先生，
you have these needs
你有这些需求
related to aviation industry.
与航空业相关。
So I think
所以我认为
the value of the data
数据的价值
should be very big in the aviation industry.
在航空业应该是很大的。
OK.
好的。
Let's continue with Rachel.
让我们继续了解雷切尔。
In addition to
此外
the whole of Hong Kong,
整个香港，
you are also working with
你也在工作
the global startup ecosystem.
全球创业生态系统。
I know that you have
我知道你有
a lot of big companies
很多大公司
and a lot of global companies.
以及许多全球性公司。
You have a lot of exchanges.
你们有很多交流。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Mr. Du, you were talking about
杜先生，您说的是
Ethereum applications.
以太坊应用程序。
There are not many applications now.
现在应用不多。
Do you think
你认为
there is still a gap
仍有差距
or a problem
or a problem
that prevents big companies
这阻碍了大公司
from doing things
从做事
on public goods
关于公共产品
like Ethereum?
像以太坊？
OK, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
This is a very
这是一个非常
difficult question.
困难的问题。
I think
我认为
there are two main aspects.
主要有两个方面。
First, in terms of
首先，就
user experience,
用户体验，
if we can do it later,
如果我们可以稍后再做的话
for example,
例如，
we can do it without feeling.
我们可以毫无感觉地做到这一点。
You are actually
你其实是
using Ethereum later.
稍后使用以太坊。
But in fact, the apps you usually use
但事实上，你经常使用的应用程序
are similar.
是相似的。
Mass adoption will be much easier.
大规模采用将会容易得多。
This is the first point.
这是第一点。
Secondly,
第二，
I think it is more advanced.
我认为这是更先进的。
It may be a balance
这可能是一种平衡
between
之间
corporate and private.
公司和私人。
I think this is
我认为这是
very important.
非常重要。
But this
但这
is also
也是
the most important
最重要的
value of
的值
Ethereum.
以太坊。
It is an open platform.
它是一个开放的平台。
There is no
没有
boundary.
边界。
Sometimes,
有时，
if you add a lot of privacy,
如果你添加很多隐私，
who can see
谁能看到
and who can't,
谁不能，
there will be
将有
some consideration and balance.
一些考虑和平衡。
So this is
所以这是
a very difficult
一个非常困难的
aspect to solve.
方面来解决。
In the past few years,
在过去的几年里，
the development of the entire ecosystem has grown.
整个生态系统的发展不断壮大。
From the level of
从水平上来说
layer 1 and layer 2,
第 1 层和第 2 层，
but there have been some changes in the last few days.
但最近几天发生了一些变化。